How many cups of coffe do you drink a day?
커피는 얼마나 마시니?
I drink 3 cups of coffee.
나는 커피 세 잔을 마신다.
I usually don't drink coffee.
나는 보통 커피를 마시지 않는다.
I like peppermint tea.
나는 페퍼민트차를 좋아한다.
Coffee makes me nervous.
커피는 나를 불안하게 한다.
I drink less coffee than others.
나는 다른 사람들보다 커피를 적게 마신다.
What kind of movie do you like.
너는 어떤 영화를 좋아하니?
once every two month.
두 달에 한 번
Who do you go to movie theater with.
너는 누구와 함께 영화관에 가니?
While seeing a movie, do you eat something?
영화를 보면서 뭐라도 먹니?
I eat popcorn and coke.
팝콘과 콜라를 먹는다.
What was the most recent movie you saw?
가장 최근에 본 영화는 무엇이었니?
The most recent movie I saw was 증인, a korean movie.
가장 최근에 본 영화는 한국영화인 증인 입니다.
Do you usually eat fast food.
너는 보통 패스트 푸드를 먹니?
How often do you eat fast food.
너는 얼마나 자주 패스트푸드를 먹니?
I don't like fast food .
나는 패스트푸드를 좋아하지 않는다.
what kind of sports do you like.
너는 어떤 종류의 스포츠를 좋아하니?
sometimes I like watching soccer match.
가끔 나는 축구 경기를 보는 것을 좋아한다.
I like taking a walk in the park.
나는 공원에서 산책하는 것을 좋아한다. -ing
I like to take a walk in the park.
나는 공원에서 산책하는 것을 좋아한다. to -
but nowadays I don't go there because of fine dust problem.
하지만 요즘은 미세먼지 문제 때문에 가지 않아.
but nowadays I don't go there because of ultra fine dust problem.
하지만 요즘은 초미세먼지 문제 때문에 가지 않아.
I like almost all jenres kinds of music.
나는 거의 모든 음악을 좋아한다. j
I like almost all kinds of music.
나는 거의 모든 음악을 좋아한다. k
fusion Korean classical music.
퓨전 국악
I used to like popsong. recentry I'm interest in old korean popsong.
나는 팝송을 좋아했었다. 최근에 나는 한국의 오래된 팝송에 관심이 있다.
I like 1960s Korean popsong.
나는 1960년대의 한국 팝송을 좋아한다.
I'm in my early fifties.
나는 50대 초반이다
I'm in my mid fifties.
나는 50대 중반이다
I'm in my late fifties.
나는 50대 후반이다
I want to start drinking coffee again form today.
나는 오늘부터 다시 커피를 마시기 시작하고 싶다.
What subject does he teach?
그는 무슨 과목을 가르치니?
How do you like your job.
너의 직업을 좋아하니? H-
Especially in the rainy season in summer.
특히 여름 장마철에는.
She entered elementry school at the age of seven.
그녀는 7살 때 초등학교에 들어갔다.
When she was 7 years old.
그녀가 7살이었을 때.
Should I do it at this age.
이 나이에 할까?
Snow turns to slush. Despite that I prefer a snowy day.
눈이 슬러시로 변한다. 그럼에도 불구하고 나는 눈이 오는 날이 더 좋다.
On a snowy day, the road is very slippery.
O눈이 오는 날에는 길이 매우 미끄럽다.
People easily fall down and get hurt.
사람들은 쉽게 넘어져서 다친다.
I cut my finger while cooking.
요리를 하다가 손가락을 베었다.
I sprained my ankle.
발목을 삐었어요.
I broken my leg while playing soccer.
축구를 하다가 다리가 부러졌다.
Wasn't it hard? when you learned to play your musical instrument.
힘들지 않았어? 네가 악기를 배울 때.
How long have you been playing your instrument?
악기를 연주한 지 얼마나 되셨어요?
It depends on my mood.
내 기분에 따라 다르다.
summer house.
여름 별장 - 별장
What do you like about city life?
도시 삶의 어떤 점을 좋아하세요?
because of convenience. Because it's convenient.
편해서
we can use big hospitals, public facilities and publick parks....
우리는 큰 병원, 공공 시설, 그리고 공원들을 이용할 수 있다.
What do you like about country life?
너는 시골 생활에 대해 무엇이 좋니?
we get fresh air,
우리는 신선한 공기를 얻는다.
The importance of fresh air is getting bigger and bigger.
신선한 공기의 중요성은 점점 커지고 있다.
A lot of diseases are increasing in big cities.
대도시에서는 많은 질병이 증가하고 있다.
We have to restore our clean environment .
깨끗한 환경을 복원해야 한다.
We have to restore our clean environment around us.
우리 주변의 깨끗한 환경을 복원해야 한다.
What efforts do you make to save our environment.
당신은 우리의 환경을 보호하기 위해 어떤 노력을 하는가?
preserve the environment.
환경을 보존하다
We need to plant more trees to purify the air.
우리는 공기를 정화시키기 위해 더 많은 나무를 심어야 한다.
water purifier.
정수기
bottle water.
생수(b)
spring water.
샘물, 생수
sea water.
바닷물
tap water.
수돗물
fresh water.
민물, 담수, 맑은물
Faucet.
수도꼭지
sink.
싱크대
Don't keep the water running.
물이 계속 흐르지 않게 해라.
Don't wash your face with the water on.
물을 틀어 놓은 채 세수를 하지 마라.
Pick up a hamberger on your way back home.
집에 오는 길에 햄버거 사다줘.
On the way to my office / on my way to my office.
사무실로 가는 길
I met my old friend.
나는 나의 옛 친구를 만났어요.
an old friend of mine.
나의 오랜 친구
I ran into my friend.
친구를 우연히 만났다.
We have to separate garabage collection for recycling.
우리는 재활용을 위해 가비지 수집품을 분리해야 한다.
Don't litter.
쓰레기를 버리지 마라
Don't litter on the street.
길거리에 쓰레기를 버리지 마라
litter hear.
여기에 쓰레기를 버려라
Do you like watching TV.
너는 TV보는 것을 좋아하니?
I don't usually watch TV.
나는 보통 TV를 보지 않는다.
Netflix and chill?
라면먹고 갈래?
How much time do you practice for your concert?
콘서트 연습은 얼마나 하니?
I make effort to be perfect on the stage.
나는 무대에서 완벽해지려고 노력한다.
What do you usally eat for breakfast.
너는 보통 아침으로 무엇을 먹니?
raw vegetables and nuts.
생채소와 견과류
Do you think it makes you healthy?
너는 그것이 너를 건강하게 만든다고 생각하니?
I feel like my body is getting lighter and lighter.
몸이 점점 가벼워지는 것 같다
You will see.
알게 될 것이다.
It has been only two weeks, I'm already feeling difference.
겨우 2주가 지났는데, 벌써 느낌이 달라.
Eating less is a shortcut to health.
적게 먹는 것이 건강의 지름길이다. e
Small diet is a shortcut to health.
적게 먹는 것이 건강의 지름길이다. s
I think Korean food is more healthier.
나는 한국음식이 더 건강에 좋다고 생각한다.
somebody recommended detox juice to me.
누군가 나에게 해독주스를 추천해줬다.
treadmill .
러닝머신
How do you make new friends?
당신은 어떻게 새 친구들을 사귀는가?
The best way is to join Enghlish meet-up.
가장 좋은 방법은 영어 모임에 참여하는 것이다.
I usually go to hongdai.
나는 보통 홍대에 간다.
How many clubs are you in.
몇 개의 클럽에 가입하셨습니까?
I communicate with them.
나는 그들과 의사소통을 한다.
What kind of club is it.
무슨 동아리인가.
What kind of addiction.
어떤 중독인가?
nowadays I perfer to make friends with those with the same hobby.
나는 요즘 같은 취미를 가진 사람들과 친구가 되고 싶어. to -
nowadays I perfer to making friends with those with the same hobby.
나는 요즘 같은 취미를 가진 사람들과 친구가 되고 싶어. -ing
I like meeting people who have same direction in life.
I'm trying to mingle with those who have the idea of benefiting the world.
나는 세상을 이롭게 할 생각을 가진 사람들과 어울리기를 좋아해.
profit.
금전적인 이익
benefit.
이익
I can benefit from this.
나는 이것으로 이득을 볼 수 있다.
raise the quality of life.
삶의 질을 높이다
What is your plan for summer vacation.
너의 여름방학 계획은 무엇이니?
I have to save money for the future.
나는 미래를 위해 돈을 모아야 한다.